# Summary

With almost 5 years of professional experience, I have demonstrated expertise in planning and executing User Interface (UI) Design and UX configuration across various domains, including Financial, e-commerce and Payments. My skill set encompasses technologies such as ReactJS, NextJS, Redux, JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, HTML5, Core Java, SQL, Bootstrap, Node JS, C++, Python, and Adobe Experience Manager for both client-side and server-side applications. I am well-versed in analyzing DOM layouts, employing debugging tools, and utilizing Git for version control. I have a strong track record of collaborating with designers and product managers to create user-friendly interfaces for financial services and applications. My commitment to creating optimal and user-friendly web solutions, combined with my object-oriented programming skills, makes me an asset in both team and independent work settings.

#### Skills

Web Technologies	HTML5, CSS3 Media Queries, Pseudo Elements, Ajax, RESTful Services, Adobe Experience Manager, Docker, SQL, Node.js, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Python
IDE & Tools	Eclipse, Visual Studio, Atom, JIRA, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
Version Control Tools	Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket
TypeScript/ JavaScript Libraries & Frameworks	ReactJS, NextJS, Redux, Angular (Versions 15 and 2), React Semantic UI, Material UI, AG-Grid, Ant-Design, Redux Toolkit, Redux create slice, Axios
CSS Frameworks	Ionic, React Semantic UI, Ant Design, Material UI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, AG Grid
Data Access	MYSQL, RESTful Services, Integration of HTTP requests
Build Tools	Webpack, Babel, MAVEN, NPM.
Other	Custom Reusable React Components, Forms, Events, Routers, Form validation, Reactive forms, Closures, Promises, Prototypal inheritance, Modular functions

# **Experience**

#### **Ecommerce Developer Grad Extern** – Amtrak • Washington, D.C.

07/2023 – Present

- Developing description and testing code for web and mobile applications using modern methods of development across the full stack (frameworks, web services, etc.) in general and the frontend in particular.
- Troubleshoot and resolve application issues.
- Interact with team members (end-users, testers, distributors, analysts, and project/release managers) in a teamoriented fashion.
- Support projects throughout the entire Software Development Lifecycle. Follow software development methodologies and best practices.
- Provide end-user application support & adhere to web security best practices implement code fixes under the direction of software architects and senior developers.

## **Ecommerce Developer Intern** – Amtrak • Washington, D.C.

03/2023 - 05/2023

- Participate in the creation and testing of code for web and mobile applications, while gaining exposure to contemporary development approaches throughout different layers of the technology stack, with a specific emphasis on front-end development.
- Work in cooperation with team members, which includes end-users, testers, distributors, analysts, and project/release managers, to make contributions to the development process in a collaborative team-oriented manner.
- Aid in projects across multiple phases of the Software Development Lifecycle, while gaining expertise in and implementing software development methodologies and best practices.
- Provide support for end-users at the application level and adhere to web security best practices when assisting in resolving code issues, with guidance and supervision from software architects and senior developers.
- Contribute to the enhancement of our suite of automated tests and testing infrastructure.

### Senior Software Engineer – WML IT Solutions • India

11/2019 - 01/2022

- Developed and implemented front-end architecture to support user interface concepts with 100% accuracy and develop server-side web applications using Next.js framework along with Node.js and multiple CSS frameworks.
- Exploring new features to match current User Interface trends.
- Responsible for end-to-end development of the project.
- Responsible for end-to-end delivery by connecting with functionals to understand the requirement and deliver the same.
- Improved the efficiency of the developed objects using performance tuning techniques.
- Optimized react components for maximum performance.
- Leading web application development for the project.
- Responsible for assessing, reviewing and bug fixes.

#### Full Stack Developer – WML IT Solutions • India

12/2017 - 10/2019

- Responsible for API design and development of RESTful services for the enterprise product in the business.
- Worked on building Angular, ReactJS components for the web app which improved the performance of the pages for the average user by significant time.
- Delivered complex objects with no dependency.
- Worked within an agile team and helped prioritize and scope major requests.
- Developed enterprise application using technologies like Angular, MySQL, Core Java along with Docker and Node.js.

## Education

Wichita State University – Master's

01/2022 - 05/2023

Achieved my master's degree with 3.81 GPA, specializing in Computer Science